NATHAN HEMESATH

1725 Coronita Dr, Fenton, MO 63026

hemesath2@gmail.com (319) 429-4274

PERSONAL STATEMENT

First and foremost, I am a self-starter. Learning new coding languages and techniques is exciting. Through my variety of work experience, I've had the opportunity to discover that my passion lies in a field where I can work with a team to create a unique, exciting product for the client. I have the passion, motivation, and work ethic to be a great addition to a similarly motivated team.

EXPERIENCE

User Interface Web Developer, *VGM Forbin*

(Jan 2016 – Present)

- Translate the design team's vision for the website into code
- Create sites for a variety of industries (Medical, Banking, Restaurant, etc)
- Main coding languages/skills: HTML, CSS, JQuery, SASS/SCSS, custom animation
- Also familiar with PHP and .NET for daily tasks and debugging
- Conducted research and collaborated as part of the newly formed applications team in the early stages of future app development for the company (Languages: Swift 2, Angular JS, Node JS, and Firebase)

Intern in Web Developing, Connell Aviation Group

(Aug 2015 – Nov 2015)

- Maintained multiple Wordpress sites
- Repaired previously built sites to improve functionality for the client.

Electro-Medical Patient Care Coordinator, *VGM Group* (Nov 2014 – Dec 2016)

- Conveyed important information between insurance companies and their clients to ensure providers could supply them with much needed supplies
- Assisted patients in need of TENS/NMES units to help relieve pain and live a normal life
- Exceeded production goals which allowed insurance adjusters to lighten their workload

Warehouse Worker, *Target Food Distribution*

(Jan 2011- May 2013)

- Organized a team of warehouse employees to efficiently perform daily tasks
- Trained and directed new team members
- Volunteered and contributed as part of the General Safety Team, addressing crucial risks and precautions

EDUCATION

Associates in Web Programming and Development *Hawkeye Community College*, Waterloo, IA

Graduated 2016

Bachelors of Science – Criminology *University of Northern Iowa*, Cedar Falls, IA

Graduated 2011